

Redwood City, CA

□ (858)-877-8069 | ■ amiteshsharma877@gmail.com | ♠ https://amiteshksharma.github.io/ | □ amiteshksharma | □ amiteshksharma

Summary

Current full-stack software engineer for Walmart Global Tech. Industry experience in front-end development with React.js, React Native, and TypeScript and in back-end development with Python and Node.js. Strong understanding of the programming languages JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, and C++

Work Experience _____

Walmart Global Tech Sunnyvale, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER February 2023 - Present

- Designed and developed web application from scratch to assist business in delivering important store-related information
- · Lead discussions in estimates of providing deliverables and working with product and business to achieve their goals.
- Team lead for our web application with experience in sprint planning, delegating and breaking down tasks for sprints
- Built back-end services and UI pages for our product that sees 1M+ requests a day

Verkada San Mateo, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

June 2022 - September 2022

- Worked on CI/CD pipeline to automate testing and reduce time spent manually testing during the development cycle.
- Implemented a full-stack feature and designed database tables to comply with EU security guidelines and strengthen device security.
- · Built a cronjob with Kubernetes to inform users by email when wireless devices run low on battery.

Walmart Global Tech Remote

ECOMMERCE SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

June 2021 - August 2021

- Implemented seamless and intuitive designs to provide metrics to 1M+ in-store associates.
- · Collaborated with design team to ensure proper guidelines were followed for optimal user experience
- Wrote End-to-End tests to ensure reliability and consistency in code.

Skills___

Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C, C++, Java

Front-end React.js, React Native, React-Redux, HTML5, CSS, Figma, Recoil

Back-end Node.js, Python Flask, Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLAlchemy, CosmosDB, Apollo

Tools Git, Github, Android Studio, Xcode, Elastic search, Docker, Kubernetes

Education _

UCSD (University of California, San Diego)

La Jolla, CA

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

September 2019 - December 2022

- Current GPA 3.86
- Relevant courses Discrete mathematics, algorithms, database design, compilers, machine learning, operating systems, algorithm analysis, security.

Extracurricular

Triton Software Engineering

52K monthly visits

DEVELOPER

September 2020 - December 2021

- Worked on dynamic web applications with React.js and express.js
- · Assisted nonprofit organizations with free service by building applications to help them grow and serve their everyday needs.
- Implemented front-end components for two projects: Baraka & Bilal Catering and Sakyadhita.

AMITESH SHARMA · RÉSUMÉ